Hello friends, my name is Sachin and
today I have brought a new video for you.
So friends, today we are going to talk
about Karuna Rakshak policy which is a
standard policy by IATA because all the
insurance companies were given instructions to
make this policy.
You will get this product from almost all the insurance companies
like Reliance or
ToQ or your Future Generali or there are
some other companies also,
you will get the product from them only and this product has not been
designed by me. It was
not designed by any insurance company and
keeping in mind the Corona and all the
insurance companies
were given instructions that you should buy this product. It should have some
features in it. So friends, today we are going to
review this and I will
tell you how much time it will take if you take the policy.
Almost every one of the options
is different. So friends, let's start the review of this plan.
Before moving forward, let me
tell you that if you are new to my channel, then
please subscribe
so that you keep getting all such latest
videos on insurance. And if you like this video, then
please like and share it.
Forgetting because knowledge increases by sharing, so
friends, first of all to
understand this policy we have to understand two types of insurance, that is
how many types of health insurance are there, so friends there is
insurance that you will get two types of
policies in the market, one
policy is indemnity policy, the second is
benefit policy which is an
indemnity policy, it is called
indemnity, that is any such policy which
compensates for any loss you have suffered, then
those policies are better, for example,
you have taken health insurance,
you have health insurance for 10 lakhs,
but when you are admitted in the hospital,
your bill is here or 2 lakh rupees,
then there the insurance company will give you only 2 lakh
rupees, so in this way the insurance
policy is called indemnity policy, the
second type of policies are
your benefits, friends, benefit policies are
those in which
you get full benefit,
like suppose you take a critical illness
policy, what happens in it,
suppose there is cancer or any other heart
problem, as those tests are done, you will get all the benefits for
it
We can take the example of term insurance where
if you have taken a term insurance of one crore
and here
the person dies in any way, then
his family gets one crore, so
friends, the entire benefit
amount that you get here is
told to the benefit people in one go, so friends, first of all
you should understand that the Karona
Raksha is a benefit policy, here you will
get the entire money and if we
look at the other side, the Karona Kavach policy is an
indemnity policy, that is,
for treatment in the hospital and as soon as you get this policy,
you will get the money according to its conditions, so let us
review this front, so
friends, the sum insured
available in this is first of all 50 thousand rupees,
then 1 lakh rupees, then 1.5 lakh rupees, then 2
lakh rupees, 2.5 lakh rupees, you will get these five options
inside this plan, the
entry is that any healthy person between 18 years to 65 years can
take this point,
if we look at the policy period  Talking
friends, there are three options here too which
are 105 days i.e. 360 months, 195 days i.e.
six and a half months and 285 days i.e. nine and a half
months, so friends, this is the same kind of policy
addition which is there in Karuna Kavach, if
you have not seen my previous video which is
definitely about crying, then I will
give you the link in the description and I will also give the link in the i button here, so that
you know what is the
quality of crores, so
friends, if we talk about the room here, then you will get
coverage in this policy, so
see friends, what I am telling you is that
you will get lump sum
benefit here, whichever plan you have chosen,
like remember there are positive effects
and along with that you have done a minimum 72 hours hospital
operation, then this money will be
credited to your account in your bank account, so
what will happen with this, whether you get him treated or
spend on yourself, so it is up to you, what do
you want to do with
that money, but suppose you have
taken a plan of two lakhs, then 2 lakh rupees will be
reversed in your bank account  It will be done
and at the same time this policy will be yours for 10
minutes, so
friends, let us understand a little in this line
what are the expenses, every plan has some
actions which we
can call negative points or
restrictions of the plan, so
this time is very important for us, so
let us understand that also such
expenses which are related to admission, which have been
diagnosed for you, that is, any
digestive test etc. has been done for Malviya ji
or any application of yours has been made, that is,
where you have been examined etc., then
you will not get such expenses under this policy, any such diagnosis
gas pencil which means current diagnosis and
treatment, that is, whatever treatment is being done on you, is
not related to this problem, then you will not get that money here, that
means any
treatment which is not daily related, then you will not get the money for that also, there is
a waiting period of 15 days,
friends, if you have bought the policy today, then there is
no cover for 15 days
You will get this cover from the day you start school.
If you are pregnant till the fifteenth day, then
you will not be able to get it under this policy. The
third change is testing done at a
diagnostic center authorized by the
government. So friends, here the report of whichever
government or this testing center will be
accepted, the report from anywhere else will
not be accepted. And friends, the
second biggest thing here is that if
you will get cover in these countries, then the
Government of India has
told you that you should not travel to this country,
and if you travel to that country
and become
positive there, then you will not get it right now. So
friends, whenever you take this policy, then
definitely understand this condition
before taking this policy. So friends, let us
move a little further and know
why we should buy the policy, what is the need for the policy. It is
possible that many people already have
health insurance, then they will say that
my treatment will be done through mother, so I should take it from
my policy. So friends, see
that this policy is a benefit policy, its
money is immediately credited to your account.  There will be a
hospitalization of three days like 3 and you will be
corona positive, it will be given to your account
but if you already have any
health insurance then it will
provide you money for treatment here, it may be
in your health insurance, like nowadays
we have seen that PPP money is not
available or there are some other consumer items for
which money is not available, so there is a
huge difference here between that amount
and your insurance claim bill, it may be
more there or the
insurance claim amount may be less, then with
that money you
can fill the gap between them, secondly
suppose you are hospitalized for 10 15 20 days
and it is possible that at that time
your Aravind becomes absolutely zero, you do
not have any money, you do not have money to run the family, then this
money will be very useful for
you, so
friends, even if you have good health,
you can take this policy,
so friends, come,
I have made some preventive measures for this Tokyo company,
so I will tell you  Let me explain
how much you will have to pay on the premium of each depression and the
total amount will come. So friends, if I
talk about a life insurance here and you
take a plan of all 3 months, then for the age of 26 to
50 years, it will cost you Rs 411.
Similarly, if you
take a plan of Rs 2 lakh, then
its depression is of six and a half months and if
your age is 126 to 50 years, then you will take it for Rs 1436.
So understand once that the
GST rate here is not improved. There will be
18% GST charge in it. For example,
if any premium of
yours comes to Rs 1000, then you will have to add Rs 180 to it. So
friends, in this
way, you can see the rate chart of nine and a half months here. So friends, if
you fall in this group for whom you
want to take this policy, then you
can calculate the problem accordingly. Whereas the
premium of other companies will be almost
around this. So, this  From the red chart
you will get an idea of ​​how much the premium of this policy is
according to your face,
so friends I hope
you have understood this line, if you have
understood this line then do not forget to share this video
and we will meet in the next video, thank you
very much for watching this video.